mcc.gov 2019-06-03

# Website Privacy, Policies & Notices

## Privacy Policy

This policy describes how we handle the personal information you provide to us via our website and online forms.

Federal law requires us to tell you how we collect, use, share, and protect your personal information. Federal law also limits how we can use your personal information.

Personal information may include your name; email, home, and/or business address; phone numbers; Social Security Number; Passport Number; or other information that identifies you personally.

### Information Collection and Use

If you visit our site to read or download information, such as country information about one of our projects, we collect general log information but do not collect personal information.

General log information collected may include, but is not limited to:

  * Internet Domain (e.g. “yourcompany.com” or “youruniversity.edu”)
  * Internet Protocol (IP) address
  * Operating System
  * Browser used to access the site (e.g. Internet Explorer, Safari, Firefox, Chrome)
  * Date & Time of access
  * Pages viewed upon visit
  * Demographic categories (e.g., age range and gender)
  * Market affinity categories

We use this information to measure the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, to find out what information is most viewed, and to help us make our website more useful to our visitors.

Except for law enforcement investigations, or protection of the MCC information technology infrastructure as authorized by law, we make no other attempts to identify you or your usage habits.

We use general logs for no other purposes than the purposes described above, and we regularly destroy these logs in accordance with General Records Schedules published by the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and agency record control schedule requirements.

If you leave a comment or utilize one of our online forms and voluntarily provide your personal information, we will only utilize the information you provide to respond to you or process your request.

### Use of Cookies and Tracking Technologies

There are two common kinds of Cookies:

  * A _Session Cookie_ is a line of text that is stored temporarily in your computer’s random access memory (RAM). A session cookie is destroyed as soon as you close your browser.
  * A _Persistent Cookie_ is a line of text that is saved to a file on your hard drive and is called up the next time you visit that website. This lets the website remember information about your previous visits and use of the website.

Because of MCC’s multi-web server configuration, any page that is served securely, where the URL starts with https:// (also known as SSL or secure socket layer), sets a persistent cookie that expires and is deleted after one hour. Typically, the only pages served securely are those containing web forms. This cookie ensures that you—the user—stay on the same web server and maintain the secure connection through the process of completing and submitting the web form. To opt-out of having this cookie set, visit [Web Measurement and Customization Opt-out](https://www.usa.gov/optout-instructions) at USA.gov.

Please be aware that some of the links on the MCC website may point you to a non‐MCC site that may place persistent cookies on your computer. You can expect to be notified that you are leaving the MCC site when you select one of these links.

For more information on how to “opt-out” of cookies, visit [Web Measurement and Customization Opt-out](https://www.usa.gov/optout-instructions) at USA.gov. Users opting-out of this web measurement technology will have the same access to content as users who do not.

### Third-Party Website Measurement and Customization Technologies

This website uses Google Analytics Premium to measure the number of visitors to its different sections, to find out what information is most viewed, and to help us make our website more useful to our visitors.

Google Analytics places a persistent cookie on your computer to provide this information. This cookie does not store any personally identifiable information. (This is classified as a tier 2 tracking technology according to [OMB Memo 10-22](https://policy.cio.gov/web-policy/analytics).) Learn more about [Google Analytics cookie usage on websites](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies).

To opt-out of this cookie being placed on your computer, visit:

  * [Web Measurement and Customization Opt-out](https://www.usa.gov/optout-instructions) at USA.gov,

Users opting-out of this web measurement technology will have the same access to content as users who do not.

Some pages on our site may include web content or functionality from third parties, such as embedded videos hosted by non-MCC services. For example, as of August 1, 2013, content or functionality from the following third parties may be present on some mcc.gov pages:

  * Adobe Fonts ([Privacy Policy](http://www.adobe.com/privacy.html));
  * cloud.typography ([Privacy Policy](http://www.typography.com/home/privacy.php));
  * Google ([Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en))
  * JWPlayer ([Privacy Policy](https://www.jwplayer.com/privacy/));
  * Mapbox ([Privacy Policy](https://www.mapbox.com/privacy/)); and
  * YouTube.com ([Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en))

This list will be updated on a regular basis to reflect the third party providers of content or functionality that are commonly used on our website. If you would like to receive content that is posted using one of these third-party providers without utilizing the third-party provider, please [contact us](https://www.mcc.gov/contact-us).

These third parties may use web measurement and customization technologies (such as cookies) in conjunction with the provision of this content or functionality. You should consult the privacy policies of these third parties for further information. We do not knowingly use third-party tools that place a multi-session cookie prior to the user interacting with the tool, for example by playing an embedded video. If you become aware of a third-party tool on mcc.gov that places a multi-session cookie prior to any user interaction, please [contact us](https://www.mcc.gov/contact-us).

### Sharing of Information

We do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personal information to outside marketers or third parties. Information collected via the MCC website may be shared with employees, contractors, and other service providers (such as other U.S. Government agencies) only as necessary to respond to a request, provide a service, or as otherwise authorized by law.

### Visiting Official Millennium Challenge Corporation Pages on Third-Party Websites

MCC maintains official pages or accounts on several third-party websites in order to better engage with the American public. Those websites are listed below. Your activity on those third-party sites is governed by the security and privacy policies of the third party sites. Users of third-party sites are often sharing information with the general public, user community, and/or the third-party operating the third-party site. These actors may use this information in a variety of ways. Consequently, you should review the privacy policies of third-party sites before using them and ensure that you understand how your information may be used. You should also adjust privacy settings on your account on any third-party site to match your preferences.

Information which you voluntarily submit to or publish on an MCC page or a third-party site may be treated as public information. We may, for example, publish compilations of comments collected through these MCC pages or provide them to national leaders, members of the press or other individuals outside of the federal government.

We exercise discretion to protect voluntarily submitted information if its disclosure would raise privacy concerns. Except as described above, we do not sell, rent, exchange, or otherwise disclose this information to persons or organizations outside MCC. In some cases, we may share information with other federal agencies in response to lawful law enforcement requests or to protect mcc.gov from security threats.

If you seek assistance on a matter within the jurisdiction of a federal agency, we may share your information with that agency for the limited purpose of addressing your request for assistance.

Below is the current list of official MCC pages on third-party websites:

#### Social Networks and Multimedia

  * Facebook 
  * Flickr 
  * Instagram 
  * Medium 
  * SoundCloud 
  * Twitter 

  * YouTube 

### Use Limitation

We limit the data collected from our website to meet specific business needs and to protect your privacy. From the general log information, we may be able to determine the path(s) you took on our website, but we do not know who you are, unless you voluntarily provide and consent to give that information to us, for a specified purpose.

## Accessibility

In order to ensure that MCC meets or exceeds the requirements of Section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act, we continually review our site and modify pages to remove accessibility problems for people with disabilities.

## Linking Policy

MCC links to other U.S. Government websites (domain names usually ending in “.gov”) and private organizations that we believe are relevant to our mission (domain names usually ending in “.edu,” “.com,” etc.). Once you connect with one of these linked sites, you are subject to the disclaimers, security, and privacy policies of that site.

You may link to the MCC website or any of its content. MCC requests only that you identify that the link is to an Internet resource.

## Disclaimers

### General Disclaimer

Information presented on the MCC website is considered public information and may be distributed or copied freely unless identified as being subject to copyright protection. In return, we request only that MCC be cited as the source of any information, photos, and images copied from this site and that any photo credits or bylines be similarly credited to the photographer or author.

We strongly recommend that MCC data be acquired directly from this website and not through other sources that may change the information in some way or exclude material crucial to the understanding of that information. While we make every effort to provide accurate and complete information, some information may change between site updates. Substantive changes may be noted when content is next updated.

### Disclaimer of Endorsement

The documents posted on the MCC website may contain hypertext links or pointers to information created and maintained by other public and private organizations. These links and pointers are provided for visitors’ convenience. We do not control or guarantee the accuracy, relevance, timeliness, or completeness of any linked information. Further, the inclusion of links or pointers to websites other than a MCC‐managed website is not intended to assign importance to those sites and the information contained therein, nor is it intended to endorse, recommend, or favor any views expressed, or commercial products or services offered on these outside sites, or the organizations sponsoring the sites, by trade name, trademark, manufacture, or otherwise.

Reference in this website to any specific commercial products, processes, or services, or the use of any trade, firm or corporation name is for the information and convenience of the site’s visitor’s, and does not constitute endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by the United States Government or MCC.

The views and opinions of authors expressed herein do not necessarily state or reflect those of the U.S. Government or the MCC, and shall not be used for advertising or product endorsement purposes.

### Disclaimer of Liability

Every effort is made to provide accurate and complete information. However, we cannot guarantee that there will be no errors. We make no claims, promises or guarantees about the accuracy, completeness, or adequacy of the contents of this website and expressly disclaim liability for errors and omissions in the contents of this website.

With respect to the content of this site, neither the United States Government, nor MCC, nor their employees and contractors make any warranty, expressed or implied or statutory, including but not limited to the warranties of non‐infringement of third party rights, title, and the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose with respect to content available from this MCC website or other Internet resources linked from it. Additionally, neither the U.S. Government nor MCC assume any legal liability for the accuracy, completeness, or usefulness of any information, product, or process disclosed herein nor freedom from computer virus, and do not represent that use of such information, product, or process would not infringe on privately owned rights.

### Request for Correction (RFC)

If you believe that MCC has disseminated information that does not comply with the Office of Management and Budget Information Quality Guidelines and you are directly affected by this information, then you can submit a request to have this information corrected by contacting [MCC through our website](https://www.mcc.gov/contact-us).

Include your name, mailing address, fax number, e-mail address, telephone number, and organizational affiliation, if any. MCC needs this information to respond to your Request for Correction and contact you, if necessary.

  * Describe clearly the information you believe is in error and requires correction.
  * Include the source of the information (for example, the name and date of the report or data product), the exact location of the error (for example, the page, figure, table, or Web page address), and a detailed description of the information to be corrected.
  * A copy of the specific information that the Request for Correction covers would assist the MCC in its review of your Request for Correction.
  * State specifically why the information should be corrected and, if possible, recommend specifically how it should be corrected.

### Submitting a Request for Reconsideration (RFR)

If you are dissatisfied with a MCC decision regarding your Request for Correction, you can submit a Request for Reconsideration [through our website](https://www.mcc.gov/contact-us). To submit a Request for Reconsideration you should have already submitted a Request for Correction to MCC and received a response to that request.

## Security Notice

MCC is required to protect the information we collect and maintain about you, and we will not use the web to do business with you unless we can do so in a secure manner. We take reasonable precautions to maintain the security, confidentiality, and integrity of the information collected via the MCC website.

Below are some of the steps we take to secure the information we collect:

  * Employ role‐based access controls to ensure that the only people who see your information are those with a need to do so to perform their official duties;
  * Train personnel on our privacy and security policies to know requirements for compliance;
  * Secure the areas where we retain paper copies of any of the information we collect online;
  * Perform regular backups of the information we collect online to ensure against loss;
  * Use technical controls to secure the information we collect online including, but not limited to: 
    * Secure Socket Layer (SSL)
    * Encryption
    * Firewalls
    * Password protections
  * Employ external safeguards to identify and prevent unauthorized tries of outsiders to “hack” into, or cause harm to, the information contained in our systems.

Unauthorized attempts to upload or change information on this site are strictly prohibited and may be punishable/subject to prosecution under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986, and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act.

## Copyright Notice

Unless a copyright is indicated, information on the MCC website is in the public domain and may be reproduced, published or otherwise used without MCC’s permission. We request that MCC be cited as the source of the information and that any photo credits or bylines be similarly credited to the photographer or author or MCC, as appropriate. If a copyright is indicated on a photo, graphic, or any other material, permission to copy these materials must be obtained from the original source. This copyright notice does not pertain to information at websites other than this website.
